<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>i.am.z.grim.shell</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/</link><description>Streaming bits, wasting electrons</description><atom:link href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 13:06:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Interesting? :)</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interesting.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;On Distrowatch Debian has more points than Ubuntu and Red Hat combined - coincidence? I don't think so! ;)&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>red hat</category><category>ubuntu</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interesting.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 02:13:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Merry Christmas</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/merry-christmas.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today it is Christmas here (Serbs are majority Orthodox and so is my family). While I am not religious, it has a great tradition here and probably the only day when majority of family gathers on one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also today remember my Debian family and want to express love to it. I will try this year to dedicate much more time to Debian and hope I keep this pace going on for many years (lifetime?) to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers to all and happy hacking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>christmas</category><category>debian</category><category>dedication</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/merry-christmas.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 15:09:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Thank you ancenstor</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/thank-you-ancenstor.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I found out that our founding father died it really was hard for me. I took it like a real man. I cried and then I choose to write a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never met Ian, but he changed my life with his humble but great decision some 22 years ago. Not only mine. He changed many of us. He empowered us, he gave us something we didn't have before. Without Debian I would never be person I am today and I am happy to say that I am still growing with incredible pace everyday. Every. Single. Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all are Ian and we will continue to keep up the fire on the torch. I can say one thing, in coming decades and centuries society is gonna get better and I am sure it will be because of Debian. Debian community will overtake the world because we are not only universal OS, we are social movement for better life where many of people I love found their home. You know, the swirl is the gear that keeps one awesome family keep going on and growing every single day. And I can be proud to say, I lived in time where Ian made a choice that changed the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you founding father, you will be remembered and celebrated forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>father</category><category>founder</category><category>ian</category><category>life</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/thank-you-ancenstor.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:23:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Deepin switches to Debian Sid</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/deepin-switches-to-debian-sid.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distribution that I feel fond of their work on UX for Linux ecosystem has switched from Ubuntu to Debian. So now pabs will probably invite them to our Derivate Census and they start packaging their stack into Debian directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More about their latest RC release and the mention of switch is on their &lt;a href="http://blog.deepin.org/2015/12/deepin-15-rc-make-you-only-have-eyes-for-us-by-the-sincerity/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>deepin</category><category>linux</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/deepin-switches-to-debian-sid.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 17:49:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What is wrong with Jolla?</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/what-is-wrong-with-jolla.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jolla management really seems to not understand a first thing about how to deal with consumers. They "sailed" on wings people believing it will be open source product. They got litterally hunderds of request and question for why it isn't? Answers, I found once something along in these lines "we plan in future".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reallity - they aren't a good company. They still didn't ship tablets, they don't even know how to deal with that, they don't answer on people question and they even don't issue refunds for people that gave money for tablets. Jolla, you suck! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They got some new funding with it but their blog post about it also sucks big time. Unless they open source SailfishOS they will go nowhere nor do I have any further interest in such bad behavior of one company that plays on community feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a better experience and more open source then you should go with Tizen, FirefoxOS (although Mozilla closed development), Cyanogen, Android, Replicant and so on...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>community</category><category>jolla</category><category>oss</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/what-is-wrong-with-jolla.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 11:25:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Just read LWN or make your news</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/just-read-lwn-or-make-your-news.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So it has been always a pain but lately going and (yes, my mistake) reading Phoronix news is just horrible (the best word I could choose, other were much more nasty). So instead writing thousand of words I just choose to make a picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="moronix" src="https://zgrimshell.github.io/images/moronix.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it's pretty much clear what it is. Instead of that people should read LWN or I should start making news because it is not hard to be waaaay much better then Phoronix guy but also news that I didn't write I will not just link to it (many times not even that) and then say how I wrote article! You know, it is fine not to understand everything and ask people questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux</category><category>lwn</category><category>news</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/just-read-lwn-or-make-your-news.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 14:08:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Okay, wow!</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/okay-wow.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not wow. BUT WOW WOW WOW!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/plane"&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; just blown my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is no measure of health to be well adjusted to a profoundly sick society - Jiddu Krishnamurti&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>human</category><category>life</category><category>universe</category><category>xkcd</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/okay-wow.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 19:48:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Think about it</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/think-about-it.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NdSD07U5uBs"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; should be watched by every single person that cares to make something out of their life. It is so awesome and I don't want to spoil it by talking about it but I at least suggest that everyone in Debian community should take an hour and watch it. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>life</category><category>think</category><category>wow</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/think-about-it.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 16:21:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Elena Grandi</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of fresh additions to Debian family, and thus wider FLOSS family is Elena Grandi. She is from realms of Valhalla and is setting her footprint into the community. A hacker mindset, a Free software lover and a 3D printing maker. Elena has big dedication to make the world free and better place for all. She tries to push limits on personal level with much care and love, and FLOSS community will benefit from her work and way of life in future. So what has the Viking lady to say about FLOSS? Meet Elena "of Valhalla" Grandi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (12 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>hackers</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 14:23:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The big life adventure called DebConf15</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/the-big-life-adventure-called-debconf15.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the help of sponsorship I managed again to attend the conference where Debian family gathers. This is going to be a mix without any particular order of everything, anything and nothing else ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="attendance pic" src="https://zgrimshell.github.io/images/debhere.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived to Heidelberg Main Train Station around 9am on 15th August and almost right away found Debian people so it made my trip to hostel easier. After arrival I checked in but needed to wait for 3 hours to get the key (it seems that SA will not have that problem at all, which is already an improvement). Although waiting was 3 hours long, it wasn't actually difficult at all as I started hugging and saying hi to many old (the super old super friend of mine - moray, or how I call him, "doc") and new friends. I just must say - if you know or don't know Rhonda, try to get somehow into her hugs. With her hug I acknowledged that I really did arrive to reunion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/the-big-life-adventure-called-debconf15.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (14 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debconf15</category><category>debian</category><category>life</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/the-big-life-adventure-called-debconf15.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 10:38:12 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>