<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>i.am.z.grim.shell</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/</link><description>Streaming bits, wasting electrons</description><atom:link href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 14:24:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>4 months of work turned into GNOME, Debian testing based tablet</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/4-months-of-work-turned-into-gnome-debian-testing-based-tablet.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Huh, where do I start. I started working for a great CEO and great company known as &lt;a href="https://puri.sm"&gt;Purism&lt;/a&gt;. What is so great about it? First of all, CEO (Todd Weaver), is incredible passionate about Free software. Yes, you read it correctly. Free software. Not Open Source definition, but Free software definition. I want to repeat this like a mantra. In Purism we try to integrate high-end hardware with Free software. Not only that, we want our hardware to be Free as much as possible. No, we want to make it entirely Free but at the moment we don't achieve that. So instead going the way of using older hardware (as Ministry of Freedom does, and kudos to them for making such option available), we sacrifice this bit for the momentum we hope to gain - that brings growth and growth brings us much better position when we sit at negotiation table with hardware producers. If negotiations even fail, with growth we will have enough chances to heavily invest in things such as openRISC or freeing cellular modules. We want to provide in future entirely Free hardware&amp;amp;software device that has integrated security and privacy focus while it is easy to use and convenient as any other mainstream OS. And we choose to currently sacrifice few things to stay in loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely that can't be the only thing - and it isn't. Our current hardware runs entirely on Free software. You can install Debian main on it and all will work out of box. I know I did this and enjoy my Debian more than ever. We also have margin share program where part of profit we donate to Free software projects. We are also discussing a lot of new business model where our community will get a lot of influence (stay tuned for this). Besides all this, our OS (called PureOS - yes, a bit misfortune that we took the name of dormant distribution), was Trisquel based but now it is Debian testing based. Current PureOS 2.0 is coming with default DE as Cinnamom but we are already baking PureOS 3.0 which is going to come with GNOME Shell as default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this important? Well, around 12 hours ago we launched a &lt;a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/librem-11-a-2-in-1-to-protect-your-digital-life#/"&gt;tablet campaign on Indiegogo&lt;/a&gt; which comes with GNOME Shell and PureOS as default. Not one, but two tablets actually (although we heavily focus on 11" one). This is the product of mine 4 months dedicated work at Purism. I must give kudos to all Purism members that pushed their parts in preparation for this campaign. It was hell of a ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Librem11" src="https://zgrimshell.github.io/images/librem11.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also approached (of course!) Debian for creation of OEM installations ISOs for our Librem products. This way, with every sold Librem that ships with Debian preinstalled, Debian will get donation. It is our way to show gratitude to Debian for all the work our community does (yes, I am still extremely proud Debian dude and I will stay like that!). Oh yes, I am the chief technology person at Purism, and besides all goals we have, I also plan (dream) about Purism being the company that has highest number of Debian Developers. In that terms I am very proud to say that Matthias Klumpp became part of Purism. Hopefully we soon extend the number of Debian population in Purism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I think it is fairly known that I am easy to approach so if anyone has any questions (as I didn't want this post to be too long) feel free to contact me. Also - in Free software spirit - we welcome any community engagement, suggestion and/or feedback.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>purism</category><category>tablet</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/4-months-of-work-turned-into-gnome-debian-testing-based-tablet.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 13:47:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>FSF has also fund raising campaign</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/fsf-has-also-fund-raising-campaign.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Free Software Foundation is also in process of funding and if you want them to shine still (or you simply love GNU manifesto or many other things this project has done for us in last 3 decades) then please support their &lt;a href="http://www.fsf.org/appeal?pk_campaign=2015-2016-fundraiser-banner-gnu&amp;amp;pk_kwd=appeal"&gt;fund raising campaign&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets create GNU world!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>freedom</category><category>fsf</category><category>gnu</category><category>linux</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/fsf-has-also-fund-raising-campaign.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 13:48:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Two short notes</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/two-short-notes.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;First: I am in Heidelberg next ~10 days so if anyone wants to meet up for a beer, keysigning and chats about FLOSS world, I am very happy to do that. Mail or ping me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second: After partnership with Microsoft, I lost interest and a bit of trust in Linux Foundation. After &lt;a href="https://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/39546.html"&gt;this move&lt;/a&gt; I am in total distrust with them and don't want them even represent Linux at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you really care about FLOSS world and your community (thus being socially responsible person) please do donate to &lt;a href="https://sfconservancy.org/supporter/"&gt;Software Freedom Conservancy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>heidelberg</category><category>linux</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/two-short-notes.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 10:06:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Happy New Year (again?)</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/happy-new-year-again.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes again, I like it that way. Twice! Anyway, we have here what is called Serbian New Year (it is again, Orthodox by Julian calendar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you missed or think you can do better New Year's resolutions - feel free to join the party (just a notice, besides firework we have a lot of gun fire here during that time. A LOT.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advice for everyone's resolution list: be better version of yourself, have more happy days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers. (oh, yes, get more involved in Debian)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>new year</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/happy-new-year-again.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 01:00:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interesting? :)</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interesting.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;On Distrowatch Debian has more points than Ubuntu and Red Hat combined - coincidence? I don't think so! ;)&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>red hat</category><category>ubuntu</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interesting.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 02:13:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Merry Christmas</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/merry-christmas.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today it is Christmas here (Serbs are majority Orthodox and so is my family). While I am not religious, it has a great tradition here and probably the only day when majority of family gathers on one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also today remember my Debian family and want to express love to it. I will try this year to dedicate much more time to Debian and hope I keep this pace going on for many years (lifetime?) to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers to all and happy hacking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>christmas</category><category>debian</category><category>dedication</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/merry-christmas.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 15:09:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Thank you ancenstor</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/thank-you-ancenstor.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I found out that our founding father died it really was hard for me. I took it like a real man. I cried and then I choose to write a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never met Ian, but he changed my life with his humble but great decision some 22 years ago. Not only mine. He changed many of us. He empowered us, he gave us something we didn't have before. Without Debian I would never be person I am today and I am happy to say that I am still growing with incredible pace everyday. Every. Single. Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all are Ian and we will continue to keep up the fire on the torch. I can say one thing, in coming decades and centuries society is gonna get better and I am sure it will be because of Debian. Debian community will overtake the world because we are not only universal OS, we are social movement for better life where many of people I love found their home. You know, the swirl is the gear that keeps one awesome family keep going on and growing every single day. And I can be proud to say, I lived in time where Ian made a choice that changed the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you founding father, you will be remembered and celebrated forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>father</category><category>founder</category><category>ian</category><category>life</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/thank-you-ancenstor.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:23:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Deepin switches to Debian Sid</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/deepin-switches-to-debian-sid.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distribution that I feel fond of their work on UX for Linux ecosystem has switched from Ubuntu to Debian. So now pabs will probably invite them to our Derivate Census and they start packaging their stack into Debian directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More about their latest RC release and the mention of switch is on their &lt;a href="http://blog.deepin.org/2015/12/deepin-15-rc-make-you-only-have-eyes-for-us-by-the-sincerity/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>deepin</category><category>linux</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/deepin-switches-to-debian-sid.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 17:49:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What is wrong with Jolla?</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/what-is-wrong-with-jolla.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jolla management really seems to not understand a first thing about how to deal with consumers. They "sailed" on wings people believing it will be open source product. They got litterally hunderds of request and question for why it isn't? Answers, I found once something along in these lines "we plan in future".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reallity - they aren't a good company. They still didn't ship tablets, they don't even know how to deal with that, they don't answer on people question and they even don't issue refunds for people that gave money for tablets. Jolla, you suck! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They got some new funding with it but their blog post about it also sucks big time. Unless they open source SailfishOS they will go nowhere nor do I have any further interest in such bad behavior of one company that plays on community feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a better experience and more open source then you should go with Tizen, FirefoxOS (although Mozilla closed development), Cyanogen, Android, Replicant and so on...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>community</category><category>jolla</category><category>oss</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/what-is-wrong-with-jolla.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 11:25:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Just read LWN or make your news</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/just-read-lwn-or-make-your-news.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So it has been always a pain but lately going and (yes, my mistake) reading Phoronix news is just horrible (the best word I could choose, other were much more nasty). So instead writing thousand of words I just choose to make a picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="moronix" src="https://zgrimshell.github.io/images/moronix.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it's pretty much clear what it is. Instead of that people should read LWN or I should start making news because it is not hard to be waaaay much better then Phoronix guy but also news that I didn't write I will not just link to it (many times not even that) and then say how I wrote article! You know, it is fine not to understand everything and ask people questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux</category><category>lwn</category><category>news</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/just-read-lwn-or-make-your-news.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 14:08:27 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>