<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>i.am.z.grim.shell (debian)</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/categories/debian.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 15:13:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Merry Christmas</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/merry-christmas.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today it is Christmas here (Serbs are majority Orthodox and so are my family). While I am not religious, it has a great tradition here and probably the only day when majority of family gathers on one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also today remember my Debian family and want to express love to it. I will try this year to dedicate much more time to Debian and hope I keep this pace going on for many years (lifetime?) to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers to all and happy hacking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>christmas</category><category>debian</category><category>dedication</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/merry-christmas.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 15:09:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Thank you ancenstor</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/thank-you-ancenstor.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I found out that our founding father died it really was hard for me. I took it like a real man. I cried and then I choose to write a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never met Ian, but he changed my life with his humble but great decision some 22 years ago. Not only mine. He changed many of us. He empowered us, he gave us something we didn't have before. Without Debian I would never be person I am today and I am happy to say that I am still growing with incredible pace everyday. Every. Single. Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all are Ian and we will continue to keep up the fire on the torch. I can say one thing, in coming decades and centuries society is gonna get better and I am sure it will be because of Debian. Debian community will overtake the world because we are not only universal OS, we are social movement for better life where many of people I love found their home. You know, the swirl is the gear that keeps one awesome family keep going on and growing every single day. And I can be proud to say, I lived in time where Ian made a choice that changed the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you founding father, you will be remembered and celebrated forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>father</category><category>founder</category><category>ian</category><category>life</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/thank-you-ancenstor.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:23:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Deepin switches to Debian Sid</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/deepin-switches-to-debian-sid.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distribution that I feel fond of their work on UX for Linux ecosystem has switched from Ubuntu to Debian. So now pabs will probably invite them to our Derivate Census and they start packaging their stack into Debian directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More about their latest RC release and the mention of switch is on their &lt;a href="http://blog.deepin.org/2015/12/deepin-15-rc-make-you-only-have-eyes-for-us-by-the-sincerity/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>deepin</category><category>linux</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/deepin-switches-to-debian-sid.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 17:49:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Elena Grandi</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of fresh additions to Debian family, and thus wider FLOSS family is Elena Grandi. She is from realms of Valhalla and is setting her footprint into the community. A hacker mindset, a Free software lover and a 3D printing maker. Elena has big dedication to make the world free and better place for all. She tries to push limits on personal level with much care and love, and FLOSS community will benefit from her work and way of life in future. So what has the Viking lady to say about FLOSS? Meet Elena "of Valhalla" Grandi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (12 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>hackers</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 14:23:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The big life adventure called DebConf15</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/the-big-life-adventure-called-debconf15.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the help of sponsorship I managed again to attend the conference where Debian family gathers. This is going to be a mix without any particular order of everything, anything and nothing else ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="attendance pic" src="https://zgrimshell.github.io/images/debhere.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived to Heidelberg Main Train Station around 9am on 15th August and almost right away found Debian people so it made my trip to hostel easier. After arrival I checked in but needed to wait for 3 hours to get the key (it seems that SA will not have that problem at all, which is already an improvement). Although waiting was 3 hours long, it wasn't actually difficult at all as I started hugging and saying hi to many old (the super old super friend of mine - moray, or how I call him, "doc") and new friends. I just must say - if you know or don't know Rhonda, try to get somehow into her hugs. With her hug I acknowledged that I really did arrive to reunion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/the-big-life-adventure-called-debconf15.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (14 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debconf15</category><category>debian</category><category>life</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/the-big-life-adventure-called-debconf15.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 10:38:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hell just got frozen</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/hell-just-got-frozen.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's at least an interesting story that Microsoft celebrated Debian release.
Once arch enemy of Linux world, now obviously on their knees when they must do
such things to sustain their business model. Next stop, Microsoft goes open
source, and still nobody cares. Then they go out of business - and no one
cares. Maybe they survive as open hardware producer? ^_^&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First they ignore you, then they laugh at you, then they fight you, then you
win. - Mahatma Gandhi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>hell</category><category>microsoft</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/hell-just-got-frozen.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 21:07:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Atlassian honors 10 years of git</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/atlassian-honors-10-years-of-git.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;and even mentions Debian.&lt;a href="https://www.atlassian.com/git/articles/10%0A-years-of-git/"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; under info for Git installations skyrocket (January 2010) and
Git installations surpass all other version control systems (January 2011).
There is also part with git-annex written by our old pal Joey Hess. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>git</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/atlassian-honors-10-years-of-git.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 20:37:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Francesca Ciceri</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-francesca-ciceri.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Debian and FLOSS community don't only occupy coding developers. They occupy
people who write news, who talk about FLOSS, who help on booths and
conferences, who create artistic forms of the community and so many others
that contribute in countless ways. A lady, that is doing many of that is
Francesca Ciceri, known in Debian as MadameZou. She is non-packaging Debian
Developer, a fearless warrior for diversity and a zombie fan. Although it
sounds intimidating, she is deep caring and great human being. So, what has
MadaZou to tell us?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-francesca-ciceri.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (11 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>geek</category><category>interviews</category><category>zou</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-francesca-ciceri.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 19:20:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Random bits</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/random-bits.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Gogs&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed today &lt;a href="https://github.com/gogits/gogs"&gt;Gogs&lt;/a&gt; and configured it
with mysql (yes, yes, I know - use postgres you punk!). I will not post
details of how I did it because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It still has "weird" coding as pointed already by others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn't have fork and pull request ability yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there was end of journey. When they code in fork/PR , I will close my eyes
on other coding stuff and try it again because Gitlab is not close to my heart
and installing their binary takes ~850MB of space which means a lot of ruby
code that could go wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/random-bits.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bits</category><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/random-bits.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 19:18:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My journey into Debian</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/my-journey-into-debian.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notice&lt;/strong&gt;: There were several requests for me to more elaborate on my path to Debian and impact on life so here it is. It's going to be a bit long so anyone who isn't interested in my personal Debian journey should skip it. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2007. I enrolled into Faculty of Mechanical Engineering (at first at
Department of Industrial Management and later transfered to Department of
Mechatronics - this was possible because first 3 semesters are same for both
departments). By the end of same year I was finishing my tasks (consisting
primarily of calculations, some small graphical designs and write-ups) when
famous virus, called by users "RECYCLER", sent my Windows XP machine into
oblivion. Not only it took control over machine and just spawned so many
processes that system would crash itself, it actually deleted all from hard-
disk before it killed the system entirely. I raged - my month old work, full
of precise calculations and a lot of design details, was just gone. I started
cursing which was always continued with weeping: "Why isn't there an OS that
can whithstand all of viruses, even if it looks like old DOS!". At that time,
my roommate was my cousin who had used Kubuntu in past and currently was
having SUSE dual-booted on his laptop. He called me over, started talking
about this thing called Linux and how it's different but de facto has no
viruses. Well, show me this Linux and my thought was, it's probably so ancient
and not used that it probably looks like from pre Windows 3.1 era, but when
SUSE booted up it had so much more beautiful UI look (it was KDE, and compared
to XP it looked like the most professional OS ever).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/my-journey-into-debian.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>journey</category><category>life</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/my-journey-into-debian.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 20:09:46 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>