<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>i.am.z.grim.shell (debian)</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/categories/debian.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 12:48:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The big life adventure called DebConf15</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/the-big-life-adventure-called-debconf15.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the help of sponsorship I managed again to attend the conference where Debian family gathers. This is going to be a mix without any particular order of everything, anything and nothing else ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="attendance pic" src="https://zgrimshell.github.io/images/debhere.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived to Heidelberg Main Train Station around 9am on 15th August and almost right away found Debian people so it made my trip to hostel easier. After arrival I checked in but needed to wait for 3 hours to get the key (it seems that SA will not have that problem at all, which is already an improvement). Although waiting was 3 hours long, it wasn't actually difficult at all as I started hugging and saying hi to many old (the super old super friend of mine - moray, or how I call him, "doc") and new friends. I just must say - if you know or don't know Rhonda, try to get somehow into her hugs. With her hug I acknowledged that I really did arrive to reunion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/the-big-life-adventure-called-debconf15.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (14 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debconf15</category><category>debian</category><category>life</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/the-big-life-adventure-called-debconf15.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 10:38:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hell just got frozen</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/hell-just-got-frozen.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's at least an interesting story that Microsoft celebrated Debian release.
Once arch enemy of Linux world, now obviously on their knees when they must do
such things to sustain their business model. Next stop, Microsoft goes open
source, and still nobody cares. Then they go out of business - and no one
cares. Maybe they survive as open hardware producer? ^_^&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First they ignore you, then they laugh at you, then they fight you, then you
win. - Mahatma Gandhi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>hell</category><category>microsoft</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/hell-just-got-frozen.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 21:07:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Atlassian honors 10 years of git</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/atlassian-honors-10-years-of-git.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;and even mentions Debian.&lt;a href="https://www.atlassian.com/git/articles/10%0A-years-of-git/"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; under info for Git installations skyrocket (January 2010) and
Git installations surpass all other version control systems (January 2011).
There is also part with git-annex written by our old pal Joey Hess. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>git</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/atlassian-honors-10-years-of-git.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 20:37:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Francesca Ciceri</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-francesca-ciceri.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Debian and FLOSS community don't only occupy coding developers. They occupy
people who write news, who talk about FLOSS, who help on booths and
conferences, who create artistic forms of the community and so many others
that contribute in countless ways. A lady, that is doing many of that is
Francesca Ciceri, known in Debian as MadameZou. She is non-packaging Debian
Developer, a fearless warrior for diversity and a zombie fan. Although it
sounds intimidating, she is deep caring and great human being. So, what has
MadaZou to tell us?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-francesca-ciceri.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (11 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>geek</category><category>zou</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-francesca-ciceri.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 19:20:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Random bits</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/random-bits.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Gogs&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed today &lt;a href="https://github.com/gogits/gogs"&gt;Gogs&lt;/a&gt; and configured it
with mysql (yes, yes, I know - use postgres you punk!). I will not post
details of how I did it because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It still has "weird" coding as pointed already by others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn't have fork and pull request ability yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there was end of journey. When they code in fork/PR , I will close my eyes
on other coding stuff and try it again because Gitlab is not close to my heart
and installing their binary takes ~850MB of space which means a lot of ruby
code that could go wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/random-bits.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bits</category><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/random-bits.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 19:18:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My journey into Debian</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/my-journey-into-debian.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notice&lt;/strong&gt;: There were several requests for me to more elaborate on my path to Debian and impact on life so here it is. It's going to be a bit long so anyone who isn't interested in my personal Debian journey should skip it. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2007. I enrolled into Faculty of Mechanical Engineering (at first at
Department of Industrial Management and later transfered to Department of
Mechatronics - this was possible because first 3 semesters are same for both
departments). By the end of same year I was finishing my tasks (consisting
primarily of calculations, some small graphical designs and write-ups) when
famous virus, called by users "RECYCLER", sent my Windows XP machine into
oblivion. Not only it took control over machine and just spawned so many
processes that system would crash itself, it actually deleted all from hard-
disk before it killed the system entirely. I raged - my month old work, full
of precise calculations and a lot of design details, was just gone. I started
cursing which was always continued with weeping: "Why isn't there an OS that
can whithstand all of viruses, even if it looks like old DOS!". At that time,
my roommate was my cousin who had used Kubuntu in past and currently was
having SUSE dual-booted on his laptop. He called me over, started talking
about this thing called Linux and how it's different but de facto has no
viruses. Well, show me this Linux and my thought was, it's probably so ancient
and not used that it probably looks like from pre Windows 3.1 era, but when
SUSE booted up it had so much more beautiful UI look (it was KDE, and compared
to XP it looked like the most professional OS ever).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/my-journey-into-debian.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>journey</category><category>life</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/my-journey-into-debian.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 20:09:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Laura Arjona</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-laura-arjona.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One of fresh additions to Debian, that is showing Debian's commitment to
diversity in all fields is Laura Arjona Reina. A helpful hand on channels and
a great flux of FLOSS energy she brings with herself. Although applied for
non-packaging Debian Developer status, Laura does recognize that there are
still some technical aspects what must grasp on. Her dedication to FLOSS and
trying to solve some of its issues is astonishing, as this woman is doing a
lot of self-hosting and system administration. Yes, you read it right - she
does all of that and still applied for non-packaging Debian Developer. She is
perfect example how FLOSS enhances humans in many ways. Hello Laura.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-laura-arjona.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (10 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>larjona</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-laura-arjona.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 19:35:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Paul Wise</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-paul-wise.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After starting with &lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/interviews-with-%0Afloss-developers-joey-hess/"&gt;Joey Hess&lt;/a&gt;, we continue with Paul Wise. What makes his star
to shine are many things such as being a DSA (Debian System Administrator), a
helpful hand on mailings list, encouraging people to join Debian teams but
most of all - he has encyclopedia knowledge on Debian as a whole which he
gladly shares with anyone who asks (very fast response on IRC channels). It is
almost impossible for any single person to count all Debian teams, work and
places - to know most of those things, you can image the vast knowledge which
Paul has. The legend says that his brain has better and faster search engine
algorithm on Debian related queries than all other engines combined. So lets
see what he has to share with world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-paul-wise.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (10 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>interviews</category><category>pabs</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-paul-wise.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 22:37:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Debian priglavci</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/debian-priglavci.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mom and Debian is an awesome combination. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Debian pape" src="https://zgrimshell.github.io/images/pape.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>mom</category><category>pape</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/debian-priglavci.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 18:56:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Joey Hess</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-joey-hess.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit: Now translated to &lt;a href="http://www.labazhou.net/2015/03/interviews-%0Awith-floss-developers-joey-hess/"&gt;Chinese&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks zhang wei!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is really hardly a better way to open a series of interviewing with
developers behind Free Libre Open Source Software project, then with
incredible mind such as Joey Hess. To write his contributions to Free software
ecosystem, especially in Debian, would be a book by itself. His impact exceeds
even his projects - people literally follow his blog posts to see what he is
doing and how is he living. A hacker from cabin. If you really need to have a
picture of true hacker, then Joey is the one. As this isn't a book I will just
mention few projects that he has been behind - git-annex, ikiwiki, etckeeper,
debian installer, parts of dpkg, debhelper, devscripts, taskel. So without
further waiting here it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-joey-hess.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>hacker</category><category>joeyh</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-joey-hess.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 19:27:17 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>