<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>i.am.z.grim.shell (family)</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/categories/family.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 16:25:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Trip to DebConf14</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/trip-to-debconf14.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;First thing first. I went with Debian invitation letter to US embassy in
Sarajewo, got accepted and after few days my passport with US visa was with
me. Got booked ticket (with help of Steve Langasek) and bought my bus ticket
to Belgrade Airport (Nikola Tesla). As bus tour would be from Banja Luka
through Croatia (the highway) and then to Belgrade I needed some special
planning to do. To be honest I needed some special plan for whole trip. You
wonder why I needed special plan?! Well because I was bringing with me 9
liters of rakija. Yep you read it correctly - 9 liters of rakija. As in most
European countries (and especially EU, which Croatia is now part) allowed
quantity was to bring 1l of it. I wasn't much nervous about it (actually I
wasn't nervous at all I just didn't want to loose the rakija ;) ) as I already
had "bus-border" experience during my previous DebConf (DebConf13 in
Switzerland). So I packed all nine liters into my backpack and put it above
where I sat. In my suitcase (that is going in suitcase space inside bus) I put
my laptop from backpack. The suitcase would most probably be checked by border
police but the backpack shouldn't be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/trip-to-debconf14.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debconf</category><category>family</category><category>trip</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/trip-to-debconf14.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 19:08:34 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>