<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>i.am.z.grim.shell (floss)</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/categories/floss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 19:51:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Elena Grandi</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of fresh additions to Debian family, and thus wider FLOSS family is Elena Grandi. She is from realms of Valhalla and is setting her footprint into the community. A hacker mindset, a Free software lover and a 3D printing maker. Elena has big dedication to make the world free and better place for all. She tries to push limits on personal level with much care and love, and FLOSS community will benefit from her work and way of life in future. So what has the Viking lady to say about FLOSS? Meet Elena "of Valhalla" Grandi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (12 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>hackers</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 14:23:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Francesca Ciceri</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-francesca-ciceri.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Debian and FLOSS community don't only occupy coding developers. They occupy
people who write news, who talk about FLOSS, who help on booths and
conferences, who create artistic forms of the community and so many others
that contribute in countless ways. A lady, that is doing many of that is
Francesca Ciceri, known in Debian as MadameZou. She is non-packaging Debian
Developer, a fearless warrior for diversity and a zombie fan. Although it
sounds intimidating, she is deep caring and great human being. So, what has
MadaZou to tell us?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-francesca-ciceri.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (11 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>geek</category><category>interviews</category><category>zou</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-francesca-ciceri.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 19:20:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Random bits</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/random-bits.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Gogs&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed today &lt;a href="https://github.com/gogits/gogs"&gt;Gogs&lt;/a&gt; and configured it
with mysql (yes, yes, I know - use postgres you punk!). I will not post
details of how I did it because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It still has "weird" coding as pointed already by others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn't have fork and pull request ability yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there was end of journey. When they code in fork/PR , I will close my eyes
on other coding stuff and try it again because Gitlab is not close to my heart
and installing their binary takes ~850MB of space which means a lot of ruby
code that could go wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/random-bits.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bits</category><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/random-bits.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 19:18:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Laura Arjona</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-laura-arjona.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One of fresh additions to Debian, that is showing Debian's commitment to
diversity in all fields is Laura Arjona Reina. A helpful hand on channels and
a great flux of FLOSS energy she brings with herself. Although applied for
non-packaging Debian Developer status, Laura does recognize that there are
still some technical aspects what must grasp on. Her dedication to FLOSS and
trying to solve some of its issues is astonishing, as this woman is doing a
lot of self-hosting and system administration. Yes, you read it right - she
does all of that and still applied for non-packaging Debian Developer. She is
perfect example how FLOSS enhances humans in many ways. Hello Laura.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-laura-arjona.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (10 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>interviews</category><category>larjona</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-laura-arjona.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 19:35:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Paul Wise</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-paul-wise.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After starting with &lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/interviews-with-%0Afloss-developers-joey-hess/"&gt;Joey Hess&lt;/a&gt;, we continue with Paul Wise. What makes his star
to shine are many things such as being a DSA (Debian System Administrator), a
helpful hand on mailings list, encouraging people to join Debian teams but
most of all - he has encyclopedia knowledge on Debian as a whole which he
gladly shares with anyone who asks (very fast response on IRC channels). It is
almost impossible for any single person to count all Debian teams, work and
places - to know most of those things, you can image the vast knowledge which
Paul has. The legend says that his brain has better and faster search engine
algorithm on Debian related queries than all other engines combined. So lets
see what he has to share with world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-paul-wise.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (10 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>interviews</category><category>pabs</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-paul-wise.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 22:37:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Joey Hess</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-joey-hess.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit: Now translated to &lt;a href="http://www.labazhou.net/2015/03/interviews-%0Awith-floss-developers-joey-hess/"&gt;Chinese&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks zhang wei!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is really hardly a better way to open a series of interviewing with
developers behind Free Libre Open Source Software project, then with
incredible mind such as Joey Hess. To write his contributions to Free software
ecosystem, especially in Debian, would be a book by itself. His impact exceeds
even his projects - people literally follow his blog posts to see what he is
doing and how is he living. A hacker from cabin. If you really need to have a
picture of true hacker, then Joey is the one. As this isn't a book I will just
mention few projects that he has been behind - git-annex, ikiwiki, etckeeper,
debian installer, parts of dpkg, debhelper, devscripts, taskel. So without
further waiting here it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-joey-hess.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>hacker</category><category>interviews</category><category>joeyh</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-joey-hess.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 19:27:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nightmare</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/nightmare.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had last night a dream. It was really bad - systemd took over the Linux
ecosystem, distributions became very similar and after some time every piece
of Free software gathered all their contributors in one place and they decided
to create one superb GNU/Linux OS with a manpower of all FLOSS contributors.
So now Google, Apple, Microsoft and all other parties that try to centralize
their power in world had an adversary of millions hackers forking ideas of
their software and creating by a magnitude better FLOSS equivalents and give
power to people. When I woke up I did a fsck do Google, Apple, Microsoft and
other parties exist still at all. All good - the world is same as it was
yesterday, people don't have the power (thanks to jobs)...&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>floss</category><category>hackers</category><category>systemd</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/nightmare.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:57:35 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>