<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>i.am.z.grim.shell (founder)</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/categories/founder.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:35:59 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Thank you ancenstor</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/thank-you-ancenstor.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I found out that our founding father died it really was hard for me. I took it like a real man. I cried and then I choose to write a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never met Ian, but he changed my life with his humble but great decision some 22 years ago. Not only mine. He changed many of us. He empowered us, he gave us something we didn't have before. Without Debian I would never be person I am today and I am happy to say that I am still growing with incredible pace everyday. Every. Single. Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all are Ian and we will continue to keep up the fire on the torch. I can say one thing, in coming decades and centuries society is gonna get better and I am sure it will be because of Debian. Debian community will overtake the world because we are not only universal OS, we are social movement for better life where many of people I love found their home. You know, the swirl is the gear that keeps one awesome family keep going on and growing every single day. And I can be proud to say, I lived in time where Ian made a choice that changed the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you founding father, you will be remembered and celebrated forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>father</category><category>founder</category><category>ian</category><category>life</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/thank-you-ancenstor.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:23:05 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>