<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>i.am.z.grim.shell (hackers)</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/categories/hackers.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 14:30:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Interviews with FLOSS developers: Elena Grandi</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of fresh additions to Debian family, and thus wider FLOSS family is Elena Grandi. She is from realms of Valhalla and is setting her footprint into the community. A hacker mindset, a Free software lover and a 3D printing maker. Elena has big dedication to make the world free and better place for all. She tries to push limits on personal level with much care and love, and FLOSS community will benefit from her work and way of life in future. So what has the Viking lady to say about FLOSS? Meet Elena "of Valhalla" Grandi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (12 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>floss</category><category>hackers</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/interviews-with-floss-developers-elena-grandi.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 14:23:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nightmare</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/nightmare.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I had last night a dream. It was really bad - systemd took over the Linux
ecosystem, distributions became very similar and after some time every piece
of Free software gathered all their contributors in one place and they decided
to create one superb GNU/Linux OS with a manpower of all FLOSS contributors.
So now Google, Apple, Microsoft and all other parties that try to centralize
their power in world had an adversary of millions hackers forking ideas of
their software and creating by a magnitude better FLOSS equivalents and give
power to people. When I woke up I did a fsck do Google, Apple, Microsoft and
other parties exist still at all. All good - the world is same as it was
yesterday, people don't have the power (thanks to jobs)...&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>floss</category><category>hackers</category><category>systemd</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/nightmare.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:57:35 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>