<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>i.am.z.grim.shell (journey)</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/categories/journey.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 16:25:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>My journey into Debian</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/my-journey-into-debian.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notice&lt;/strong&gt;: There were several requests for me to more elaborate on my path to Debian and impact on life so here it is. It's going to be a bit long so anyone who isn't interested in my personal Debian journey should skip it. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2007. I enrolled into Faculty of Mechanical Engineering (at first at
Department of Industrial Management and later transfered to Department of
Mechatronics - this was possible because first 3 semesters are same for both
departments). By the end of same year I was finishing my tasks (consisting
primarily of calculations, some small graphical designs and write-ups) when
famous virus, called by users "RECYCLER", sent my Windows XP machine into
oblivion. Not only it took control over machine and just spawned so many
processes that system would crash itself, it actually deleted all from hard-
disk before it killed the system entirely. I raged - my month old work, full
of precise calculations and a lot of design details, was just gone. I started
cursing which was always continued with weeping: "Why isn't there an OS that
can whithstand all of viruses, even if it looks like old DOS!". At that time,
my roommate was my cousin who had used Kubuntu in past and currently was
having SUSE dual-booted on his laptop. He called me over, started talking
about this thing called Linux and how it's different but de facto has no
viruses. Well, show me this Linux and my thought was, it's probably so ancient
and not used that it probably looks like from pre Windows 3.1 era, but when
SUSE booted up it had so much more beautiful UI look (it was KDE, and compared
to XP it looked like the most professional OS ever).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/my-journey-into-debian.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>debian</category><category>journey</category><category>life</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/my-journey-into-debian.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 20:09:46 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>