<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>i.am.z.grim.shell (tor)</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://zgrimshell.github.io/categories/tor.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 05:49:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Take that boredom</title><link>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/take-that-boredom.html</link><dc:creator>Zlatan Todoric</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I was bored on Defcon, I took the smallest VPS in DO offering (512MB RAM, 20GB disk), configured nginx on it, bought domain zlatan.tech and cp'ed my blog data to blog.zlatan.tech. I thought it will just be out of boredom and tear it apart in a day or two but it is still there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only that, the droplet came with Debian 8.5 but I just added unstable and experimental to it and upgraded. Just to experiment and see what time will I need to break it. To make it even more adventurous (and also force me to not take it too much serious, at least at this point) I did something on what Lars would scream - I did not enable backups!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While having fun with it I added letsencrypt certificate to it (wow, that was quite easy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I installed and configured Tor. Ende up adding an .onion domain for it! It is: pvgbzphm622hv4bo.onion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main blog is still going to be zgrimshell.github.io (for now at least) where I push my Nikola (static site generator written in python) generated content as git commits. To my other two domains (on my server) I just rsync the content now. Simple and efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must admit I like my blog layout. It is simple, easy to read, efficient and fast, I don't bother with comments and writing a blog in markdown (inside terminal as all good behaving hacker citizen) while compiling it with Nikola is breeze (and yes, I did choose Nikola because of Nikola Tesla and python). Also I must admit that nginx is pretty nice webserver, no need to explain the beauty of git but I can't recommend enough of rsync.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone is interested in doing the same I am happy to talk about it but these tools are really simple (as I enjoy simple things and by simple I mean small tools, no complicated configs and easy execution).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blog</category><category>debian</category><category>nginx</category><category>tor</category><guid>https://zgrimshell.github.io/posts/take-that-boredom.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 05:45:02 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>